Clement Fung

Email: clementf@andrew.cmu.edu Website: https://clementfung.me

SUMMARY

Machine learning models present a unique threat model. As a result, when machine learning is integrated into real-world systems, the underlying assumptions and threats change. My research explores how these changes affect the privacy and security of such systems when they are deployed for real-world use. Most notably, I am interested in attacks and defenses for distributed multi-party machine learning systems (such as federated learning) and the security and explainability of machine-learning-based cyber-physical systems.

PUBLICATIONS

Refereed publications

• Biscotti: A Blockchain System for Private and Secure Federated Learning

Muhammad Shayan, Clement Fung, Chris J.M. Yoon, Ivan Beschastnikh. *IEEE Transactions on Parallel and Distributed Systems (TPDS)*

Volume 32, Issue 7. July 2021.

• Towards a Lightweight, Hybrid Approach for Detecting DOM XSS Vulnerabilities with Machine Learning

William Melicher, Clement Fung, Lujo Bauer, Limin Jia.

The Web Conference 2021

Ljubjana, Slovenia (Virtual). April 2021.

• The Limitations of Federated Learning in Sybil Settings

Clement Fung, Chris J.M Yoon, Ivan Beschastnikh.

23rd International Symposium on Research in Attacks, Intrusions and Defenses (RAID 2020) Donostia/San Sebastian, Spain (Virtual). October 2020.

• Brokered Agreements in Multi-Party Machine Learning

Clement Fung, Ivan Beschastnikh.

10th ACM SIGOPS Asia-Pacific Workshop on Systems (APSys 2019)

Hangzhou, China, August 2019.

• GainForest: Scaling Climate Finance for Forest Conservation using Interpretable Machine Learning on Satellite Imagery

David Dao, Catherine Cang, <u>Clement Fung</u>, Ming Zhang, Nick Pawlowski, Reuven Gonzales, Nick Beglinger, Ce Zhang.

Climate Change: How Can AI Help?: ICML 2019 Workshop

Long Beach, CA, June 2019.

Pre-prints

• Dancing in the Dark: Private Multi-Party Machine Learning in an Untrusted Setting Clement Fung, Jamie Koerner, Stewart Grant, Ivan Beschastnikh.

ArXiv Preprint: 1811.09712

November 2018.

• Mitigating Sybils in Federated Learning Poisoning

Clement Fung, Chris J.M. Yoon, Ivan Beschastnikh.

ArXiv Preprint: 1808.04866

August 2018.

EDUCATION

PhD, Societal Computing, School of Computer Science

2019 - present

Carnegie Mellon University, Pittsburgh, PA

Cumulative GPA: 3.87 / 4

Research Projects:

- DOM-XSS-ML: A hybrid, machine learning system to detect DOM-XSS with reduced overhead
- ICS-ML: Securing industrial control systems with machine-learning-based anomaly detection

Graduate Courses:

- 18731 Network Security (Prof. Vyas Sekar)
- 17762 Law of Computer Technology (*Prof. Michael Shamos*)
- 36700 Probability and Mathematical Statistics (*Prof. Valerie Ventura*)
- 18739 Security and Fairness of Deep Learning (Prof. Piotr Mardziel)
- 18730 Introduction to Computer Security (Prof. Virgil Gligor)

MSc, Computer Science

2016 - 2018

University of British Columbia, Vancouver, BC Cumulative GPA: 88 / 100

Thesis:

• Dancing in the Dark: Private Multi-Party Machine Learning in an Untrusted Setting. Supervisor: Ivan Beschastnikh

Achievements:

- UBC CS Department Graduate Teaching Assistant Award, 2017
- UBC CS Department Student Service Award, 2017

Research Projects:

- Biscotti: A secure, private blockchain-based system for multi-party machine learning
- FoolsGold: A sybil-resilient federated learning protocol against model poisoning
- TorMentor: A system for distributed, collaborative, anonymous machine learning
- InsuLearn: A system for distributed learning on private medical data
- DistributedClocks: A library for vector clock instrumentation of distributed systems

Graduate Courses:

- CPSC 532R Graphical Models (Prof. Siamak Ravanbakhsh)
- CPSC 540 Advanced Machine Learning (*Prof. Mark Schmidt*)
- CPSC 538W Data At Scale (Prof. Andrew Warfield)
- CPSC 538B Distributed Systems (*Prof. Ivan Beschastnikh*)
- CPSC 340 Machine Learning (*Prof. Mark Schmidt*)

BASc, Systems Design Engineering (Dean's Honour's List Distinction)

2011 - 2016

University of Waterloo, Waterloo, ON

Cumulative GPA: 88 / 100

Capstone Project:

• Driven: A Automated System for Intelligent Annotation and Analysis of Lane Change Sentiment Supervisor: Alexander Wong

Awards:

- Sanford Fleming Award for Co-operative Proficiency, 2016
- GM Canada Innovation Award, 2016 \$500
- W.W. King Exchange Fellowship, 2015 \$500
- President's International Experience Award, 2014 \$1500
- Sanford Fleming Award for Outstanding Communication in Work Term Report, 2013 \$300
- Colonel Hugh Heasley Engineering Scholarship, 2011 \$10000
- University of Waterloo President's Scholarship of Distinction, 2011 \$2000

Achievements:

- Dean's Honour's List, Winter 2016 Rank unknown
- Dean's Honour's List, Winter 2013 Ranked 2nd / 81 students
- Dean's Honour's List, Spring 2012 Ranked 2nd / 85 students
- Dean's Honour's List, Fall 2011 Ranked 3rd / 94 students

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

Teaching Assistant University of British Columbia	Sept 2016 - Dec 2018
• DSCI 571: Supervised Learning	Fall 2018

Instructors: Michael Gelbart, Varada Kolhatkar

• DSCI 523: Data Wrangling

Fall 2018

Instructors: Jenny Bryan, Rodolfo Lourenzutti

• CPSC 340: Machine Learning
Instructor: Michael Gelbart

CPSC 340: Machine Learning
Winter 2018

• CPSC 340: Machine Learning
Instructor: Mark Schmidt

Fall 2017

• CPSC 210: Software Construction Winter 2017 Instructors: Norman Hutchinson, Paul Carter, Mehrdad Oveisi

• CPSC 210: Software Construction Fall 2016 Instructors: Norman Hutchinson, Ryan Vogt, Jonatan Schroeder

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Research Assistant August 2019 - present

Carnegie Mellon University, Pittsburgh, PA, USA

• Research on machine learning, security and the industrial internet-of-things in CyLab.

Software Engineer

January 2019 - July 2019

Oasis Labs, Berkeley, CA, USA

• Developed applications for secure data sharing and other confidential use cases in an early stage blockchain startup.

Research Assistant

January 2017 - December 2018

University of British Columbia, Vancouver, BC, Canada

 Research on the security of machine learning systems in the Networks, Systems and Security (NSS) Lab.

Software Engineering Intern

June - August 2015

LinkedIn Corporation, Sunnyvale, CA, USA

• Analytics: Building infrastructure for online relevance scoring at scale

Software Engineering Intern

September 2014 - December 2014

LinkedIn Corporation, Mountain View, CA, USA

• Distributed Data Systems: Prototyped and designed new derived data serving system, Venice

Software Engineering Intern

January 2014 - April 2014

Voicebox Technologies, Bellevue, WA, USA

• Server and Tools: Implemented layer for concurrent database access on a mobile service

Software Developer

May 2013 - August 2013

Ontario Institute for Cancer Research, Toronto, ON

• Software developer in Paul Boutros' bioinformatics research group

Software Developer

September 2012 - December 2012

pVelocity, Toronto, ON

QA Analyst

January 2012 - April 2012

pVelocity, Toronto, ON